<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cooking on Mara&#39;s Life</title>
    <link>/tags/cooking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cooking on Mara&#39;s Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/cooking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cod Liver in Nine Acts</title>
      <link>/2022/11/12/cod-liver-in-nine-acts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2022/11/12/cod-liver-in-nine-acts/</guid>
      <description>Family visited recently and left us with nine cans of Icelandic Cod Liver. Why nine you ask? Well they had a box of twelve sent ahead of their visit and ate three of them while staying with us.
I texted a picture of my undeserved hepatic lode of Northern Atlantic goodness to med school friends and promised culinary updates in my pursuit of full turn over of the cupboard inventory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe storage</title>
      <link>/2020/04/12/recipe-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/12/recipe-storage/</guid>
      <description>For several years I have been thinking about what is the best way to store recipes for my purposes. Currently, I have a mixture of ways that serve me quite well. I send myself emails about recipes, I have some Google docs, I have sticky notes in my very few, beloved cookbooks, and I have my absolute standards on 3x5 note cards that live in a designated spot in the kitchen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooking: General Principles</title>
      <link>/2020/04/05/cooking-general-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/05/cooking-general-principles/</guid>
      <description>General PrinciplesOur home’s cooking style has several major sources of inspiration and guidance. Two are books: How to Cook Everything by Mark Bittman and The Professional Chief by the Culinary Institute of America. These books were the first serious introductions we had to cooking. We also find a wealth of inspiration from J. Kenji López-Alt at Serious Eats with special appreciation for his devotion to experimentation and crisp documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
