<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Mara&#39;s World</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Mara&#39;s World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe storage</title>
      <link>/2020/04/12/recipe-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/12/recipe-storage/</guid>
      <description>For several years I have been thinking about what is the best way to store recipes for my purposes. Currently, I have a mixture of ways that serve me quite well. I send myself emails about recipes, I have some Google docs, I have sticky notes in my very few, beloved cookbooks, and I have my absolute standards on 3x5 note cards that live in a designated spot in the kitchen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooking: General Principles</title>
      <link>/2020/04/05/cooking-general-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/05/cooking-general-principles/</guid>
      <description>General PrinciplesOur home’s cooking style has several major sources of inspiration and guidance. Two are books: How to Cook Everything by Mark Bittman and The Professional Chief by the Culinary Institute of America. These books were the first serious introductions we had to cooking. We also find a wealth of inspiration from J. Kenji López-Alt at Serious Eats with special appreciation for his devotion to experimentation and crisp documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immersive Language Learning</title>
      <link>/2020/04/05/immersive-language-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/05/immersive-language-learning/</guid>
      <description>I wrote the following in the fall of 2016 after my summer experience at Middlebury College for an 8 week immersive Russian course. I originally shared it with my instructors and posted it on my old blog. I have updated the format for Rmarkdown.
Reflections on my Middlebury experienceMy summer at Middlebury was amazing. I learned an enormous amount and met wonderful people, and importantly I am still progressing in Russian at home–even though I wish I could still be in that magical world in Vermont.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seatbelt Analysis</title>
      <link>/2020/04/05/seatbelt-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/05/seatbelt-analysis/</guid>
      <description>The following is from year ago exactly: 2020-04-05. I am digging up old work and putting it on my new website. This was some of my very first independent work. Looking back at it now, it is painful to see how messy my work was. But I love reading my little comments because it reminds me how excited I would get when something would work! I saw a comment about feeling intimidated by StackOverflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandemic projects</title>
      <link>/2020/04/04/pandemic-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/04/pandemic-projects/</guid>
      <description>COVID-19 has changed my life dramatically in the past 4 weeks. I’m still working, but my husband and son are out of state with family. When it became obvious to me that COVID-19 was descending on the city, I sent them away because there was no way for me to isolate myself in the apartment from them. Being away from them is difficult, so I am beyond thankful I live in a time of video chat and Google photos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kittens in paradise</title>
      <link>/2020/01/26/kittens-in-paradise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/26/kittens-in-paradise/</guid>
      <description>Fostering kittensIn May 2017 we fostered three kittens who were siblings. I tracked their daily weights out of curiosity and because I while I really enjoy fostering kittens, I would like some good rule of thumb for expected weight gain to help plan life around fostering (eg: Is this likely a 2 week or more of 4 week fostering gig?) The Maui Humane Society had specific weight cut offs for when kittens could be neutered (910 grams or 2 lbs), so for kittens that are socialized and healthy, this weight goal is the last hurdle before their neutering and being put up for adoption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back in the saddle</title>
      <link>/2020/01/25/back-in-the-saddle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/25/back-in-the-saddle/</guid>
      <description>This is a test of the emergency R blogdown broadcasting system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthcare specific R packages</title>
      <link>/2019/09/13/healthcare-specific-r-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/13/healthcare-specific-r-packages/</guid>
      <description>qichartsqcccomorbidity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio Cloud to Github to Website</title>
      <link>/2019/09/13/rstudio-cloud-to-github-to-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/13/rstudio-cloud-to-github-to-website/</guid>
      <description>It works!! But first it doesn’tYesterday I took some notes from a R Markdown workshop at R/Medicine 2019 and wanted to post them to my website. I ran into troubles!
I wanted to start making blogging from within RStudio Cloud easy. I use a Chromebook, and it isn’t easy to install R into my particalar Chromebook, though other Chromebooks have the capacity. I also am a huge RStudio Cloud user, so wanted to finally integrate my blogdown blog with my Rstudio Cloud and Github accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying out new things in R Markdown</title>
      <link>/2019/09/13/trying-out-new-things-in-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/13/trying-out-new-things-in-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>Make a table in RmarkdownColumn 1 left justifyColumn 2 centeredColumne 3 right justifiedABCHoly cow, that worked on the first try!
Pets not LivestockAlison Horst advised us that if our figures are more like pets than livestock, we should name them!!!
Here’s my attempt to name some figures and link them throughout the document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Medicine Conference: Day 1</title>
      <link>/2019/09/12/r-medicine-conference-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/12/r-medicine-conference-day-1/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown for MedicineAttended a workshop by Alison Hill. Here are some of my notes to future self to play with later.
Figure Labelling autodistill packagehtml_document2 yaml outputxaringanposterdownstargazertable makingdifferent themes (berlin, roma)project managementflexdashboardredocspellingwordcountaddinhtmlwidgets for RleafletgitlabDataTablesrevealjsFigure out how to…Bookdown: how to combine multiple .Rmd into a “book”Make a powerpoint presenation from Rmarkdown (my work is heavy in ppt)Best practicesProjectUse here packageHave a folder for figures to print to and saveResourceshttps://commonmark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goals as a chief resident</title>
      <link>/2019/09/02/goals-as-a-chief-resident/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/02/goals-as-a-chief-resident/</guid>
      <description>TomorrowTomorrow is my first day as the chief pediatric resident at Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center in NYC. I have lots of goals for the year, but knowing how chaotic life is in the hospital, I wanted to make sure I wrote them down before they are forgotten! I often find the workflow in hospitals is so busy that it is often to just hard enough to survive the day without building the foundation to try to have more good days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first post of the new website</title>
      <link>/2019/08/31/the-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/08/31/the-first-post/</guid>
      <description>This is my first post on my new website built with the R package blogdown, the help of many online help pages, and my lovely husband. I am using Github and Netlify as well. I don’t have the energy to write a post about how I built this, but here is the list of things that caused pain:
in my config.toml file I had replaced the baseurl default of baseurl = &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>